# SOUVIK SARKAR.

# Senior Technical Writer

 $sounix000@gmail.com \diamond (+91) 6360229130 \diamond Website$ 

#### **OVERVIEW**

**Technical Writer** with **9 years** of experience documenting software and APIs for developers and administrators, backed by **4 years** of experience as a **developer**. I develop deep technical content for an optimal developer experience using the docs-as-code paradigm and open-source tools.

## **SKILLS**

Programming Python, Bash, C/C++, Asm Markup DocBook XML, AsciiDoc Deployment Docker, Kubernetes Cloud Google Cloud Platform VCS Git (GitHub, GitLab) Images/Diagrams Inkscape, Mermaid.js VSCode, Vim

## **EMPLOYMENT**

SUSE March 2023 - Present

Senior Technical Writer

- · Maintain the SUSE Linux Enterprise guides for security hardening, compliance certifications, performance tuning, virtualization, and deployment.
- · Research, plan, and contribute to transitioning from monolithic guides to topic-based modular documentation for SUSE Linux Enterprise.
- · Collaborate with engineers, release managers, and product managers to realign the SUSE Linux Enterprise documentation with technical and business expectations.
- · Interface with the support engineering team to reinforce existing documentation and create clientspecific knowledge base articles.
- · Participate in peer reviews and mentor new technical writers in the team.
- · Technologies/Tools: SUSE Linux Enterprise, OpenSUSE Leap, Bash, Python, C, Assembly, DocBook XML, AsciiDoc, GitHub, GitLab, VS Code, Vim, JIRA, Confluence Wiki

Red Hat November 2020–March 2023

Senior Technical Writer

- · Lead documentation efforts for OpenShift CI/CD Pipelines, including triaging issues, creating documentation plans, and deciding content strategy.
- · Participated in peer reviews of documents for other products and mentored new technical writers in the team.
- · Collaborated with content strategists and product managers to realign product documentation with upstream documentation.
- · Interfaced with the support engineering team to reinforce existing documentation and create clientspecific knowledge-base articles.
- · Data analyzed to improve documentation coverage, flow, architecture, findability, and accessibility.
- · Technologies/Tools: Red Hat Enterprise Linux, Fedora Linux, Docker, Kubernetes, GCP, AWS, Golang, Bash, AsciiDoc, Markdown, Lucidchart, GitHub, GitLab, VS Code, Vim, JIRA, Tableau, Google Sheets

#### **Ribbon Communications**

January 2019–November 2020

Senior Technical Writer

- · Lead documentation efforts for SBC Core, resulting in improved customer satisfaction ratings.
- · Developed documents such as CLI reference and REST API user guide.
- · Participated in peer reviews of documents for other products and mentored new technical writers in the team.
- · Collaborated to revamp the internal style guide for easier onboarding of new technical writers.
- · Technologies/Tools: Proprietary networking and telecom hardware, Debian Linux, C++, C, Bash, OpenStack, AWS, Vim, Confluence Wiki, Snagit, JIRA

# FusionCharts (Infosoft Global Pvt. Ltd.)

March 2018–January 2019

Technical Content Writer

- · Developed and reviewed sample applications, code snippets, and content for developer documentation.
- · Implemented automation scripts to improve the operational efficiency of pre-release workflows.
- · Worked with the engineering and marketing teams to create and publish technical articles on third-party websites and blogs.
- · Technologies/Tools: macOS, JavaScript (Node.js, Vue.js, React.js), VS Code, Vim, Markdown, Lucid-chart, GitHub, Trello

Tata Elxsi

June 2016–March 2018

Consultant Technical Writer

Contractor for Ribbon Communications

- · Created and maintained Quick Start tutorials, API guides, User guides, and Release Notes.
- · Technologies/Tools: Proprietary networking and telecom hardware, Debian Linux, C++, C, Bash, OpenStack, AWS, Vim, Confluence Wiki, Snagit, JIRA

#### **Agaze Technologies**

September 2015–May 2016

Software Engineer

- · Developed internal and client-facing applications, focusing on back-end implementation.
- · <u>Technologies/Tools</u>: Ubuntu Linux, Python (Django, Flask), JavaScript (Node.js, React.js), Google <u>Cloud Platform (App Engine)</u>, Sublime Text, Vim

# Freelance/Self-employed

July 2012-August 2015

Web Developer

- · Developed websites, administered systems, and wrote technical content for blogs as a ghostwriter.
- · Technologies/Tools: Ubuntu Linux, Python, JavaScript, Sublime Text

## RECOGNITIONS

**Red Hat** - Several peer-to-peer awards from team members (including engineering) for collaboration and commitment to excellence.

Ribbon Communications - Motivate Award (2019-2020) for extraordinary performance.

Tata Elxsi - Customer Appreciation Award (2016-2017) based on client recommendation.

# **EDUCATION**

# Bachelor of Technology

2014